Edvard Bech Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 2. Edvard Bech, Ironmaster, 2; Box: 1 Folders: 6 - 9
  - Forest of Dean Iron ore company records, 1888 - 1902; 2.3; Box: 1 Folder: 8
    - Copy of Forest of Dean Iron Ore Company Balance Sheets., 1905; Item 149 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Map of Stockbridge Massachusetts., undated; Item 150 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Copy of a letter to Jorgen Bech from Henri Braem concerning the iron mines., February 9, 1892; Item 151 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Copy of a letter to Jorgen Bech from Henri Braem concerning the improvements to the iron furnace., January 22, 1894; Item 152 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Copy of a letter to Jorgen Bech from Henri Braem concerning the iron industry., January 29, 1895; Item 153 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Copy of a letter to Jorgen Bech from Henri Braem concerning the debts of the Company and the idea of selling stocks., January 16, 1896; Item 154 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Information on New York Canals, 2.4; Box: 1 Folder: 9
    - Notes on the Hudson and New York Canals., undated; Item 155 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Copy of page 615 from Delaware-Delaware and Hudson Railroad., undated; Item 156 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - “The Canaler” Fall 1993., Item 157 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Information on New York Canals., undated; Item 158 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - ‘The Iron Mine, Port Henry, N.Y.’ with attached notes., undated; Item 159 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Copy of ‘”Old Towpaths: The Story of The American Canal Era” by Alvin F. Harlow., undated; Item 160 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Card with notes., undated; Item 161 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - “The Story of the New York State Canals” by Roy G. Finch., undated; Item 162 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Maps of New York State Canals., undated; Item 163 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- 3. Danish Consul, 3; Box: 1 Folder: 10
  Series contains information on the Danish Consul
  - Information on the Danish Consul, 3.1; Box: 1 Folder: 10
    - Information on the three Bech family members who served as Danish Consul., undated; Item 164 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Notes on Edvard Bech as Danish Consul., undated; Item 165 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Information about who was president of the United States during each year that Edvard Bech was Danish Consul., undated; Item 166 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - List of addresses for Edvard Bech’s office from 1838-1889., undated; Item 167 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Copy of Article in Danish., undated; Item 168 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Letter to Viggo B. Rambusch from Sigurd concerning information about Edvard Bech as Danish Consul., February 9, 1990; Item 169 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Copy of a letter to the Foreign Office of Denmark from Edvard Bech., November 17, 1850; Item 170 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Notes on the Edvard Bech letter to the Foreign Office of Denmark., November 17, 1850; Item 171 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Copy of a letter to the Foreign Office in Copenhagen from Edvard Bech., March 26, 1856; Item 172 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Notes on the Edvard Bech letter to the Foreign Office in Copenhagen., March 26, 1856; Item 173 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Copy of Article on Edvard Bech in Danish., undated; Item 174 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Copy of a letter about the Danish Consul., undated; Item 175 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Portrait of J. C. Fremont, a friend of Edvard Bech and Republican candidate for President in 1856., undated; Item 176 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Pictures of “Ganymede and the Eagle,” a sculpture that was lent to the Metropolitan Museum of Art by Edvard Bech., undated; Item 177 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Letter to Michael Cook from Viggo B. Rambusch concerning Edvard Bech’s investment in the Cunard Lines with an attached letter to Viggo B. Rambusch from Priscilla Hoye giving the contact information for an archivist in Liverpool, England., August 3, 1990- August 27, 1990; Item 178 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Letter to Viggo B. Rambusch from Michael Cook giving information about the Cunard Lines., October 1990; Item 179 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Folder containing additional pictures of “Ganymede and the Eagle,” a sculpture that was lent to the Metropolitan Museum of Art by Edvard Bech with copies and negatives., undated; Item 180 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- 4. Rosenlund, 1880 - 2008; 4; Boxes: 1 - 2 Folders: 11 - 12, 1 - 3
  Series contains Materials related to Rosenlund, including photos, history, materials on Detlef Lienau, the National Register of Historic Sites, andHenri bream.
  - Rosenlund Pictures, 4.1; Box: 1 Folder: 11
    - Map of the Hudson Valley showing where Rosenlund was located., undated; Item 181 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Picture of Rosenlund’s main house, Edvard Bech’s home in Poughkeepsie, NY purchased in 1863 and sold in 1900., undated; Item 182 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Picture of Rosenlund., undated; Item 183 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Photograph of Rosenlund Daguerreotype. [See Also: Actual Daguerreotype], undated; Item 184 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Copy of Rosenlund Daguerreotype., undated; Item 185 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Information on this Daguerreotype from Viggo Rambusch to President of Marist college Dennis Murray as well as information on the value of Daguerreotypes in general from internet sources., August 3, 2009; Item 186 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Picture of St. Ann’s Hermitage, which had been the Bech family residence at Rosenlund., undated; Item 187 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Identification picture of people in a Bech family photograph, circa 1867. [See Also: Hanging storage for actual Bech Family photo and Box 4 for larger copy], undated; Item 188 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Notes on Rosenlund., undated; Item 189 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Page showing pictures of the St. Ann’s Hermitage: the novitiate (1908)., undated; Item 190 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - History of Rosenlund, 4.2; Box: 1 Folder: 12
    - Copy of the conveyance from Thomas Clegg to Edward Bech., April 30, 1863; Item 191 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Newspaper advertisement for the sale of Rosenlund., 1904; Item 192 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Copy of the “Annals of St. Ann’s Hermitage, Poughkeepsie New York 1904-1934. Translated from the French by Adrian N. Perreault- Part One (1904-1926)”, Item 193 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Excerpt from T. F. Heffernon’s senior thesis - Marist College., 1967; Item 194 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - List of sources about John Winslow., undated; Item 195 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Letter to Viggo B. Rambusch from Professor Thomas Casey suggesting a book to look into., February 1, 1990; Item 196 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Microfilm Service Bill from the New York Historical Society to Viggo B. Rambusch., February 24, 1990; Item 197 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Letter to Viggo B. Rambusch from Walter Averill concerning additional information about the Bech family and suggesting contact with Dr. Murray of Marist College., September 13, 1990; Item 198 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Letter to Viggo B. Rambusch from Walter Averill concerning the history of the Marist campus and a draft of the application for the National Register of Historical Buildings, along with a copy of that draft., November 1, 1990; Item 199 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Note to Catha Rambusch, thanking her for a letter of recommendation and sending a picture of a garden., February 16, 2003; Item 200 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Written information on Rosenlund by Viggo B. Rambusch., undated; Item 201 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Detlef Lienau: Biographies and Sketches, 4.3; Box: 2 Folder: 1
    - Sources for information on Detlef Lienau from “ American Architects VI.”, undated; Item 202 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Short biography on Detlef Lienau from “Who was Who in America.”, undated; Item 203 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Biography of Detlef Lienau from “Macmillan Encyclopedia of Architects.”, undated; Item 204 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Biography of Detlef Lienau from “Dictionary of American Biography.”, undated; Item 205 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Biographical Information on Detlef Lienau., undated; Item 206 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Inventory of Detlef Lienau’s Rosenlund Portfolio., undated; Item 207 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Drawings of the plans for the stable and coach house at Rosenlund., undated; Item 208 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Sketches of the carriage house, now Greystone., undated; Item 209 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Plans for the gardener’s lodge., undated; Item 210 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Plans for Rosenlund’s gatehouse., undated; Item 211 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Detlef Lienau’s plans for the Bech Villa., undated; Item 212 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Slides of Detlef Lienau’s plans for Rosenlund., undated; Item 213 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Slides of Detlef Lienau’s plans for Rosenlund., undated; Item 214 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Avery Library Drawings Collection list., undated; Item 215 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Inventory of Detlef Lienau’s works., undated; Item 216 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Letter to Catha Grace Rambusch from Janet Parks concerning an order of slides and a Lienau exhibit., March 21, 1990; Item 217 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Letter to Viggo B. Rambusch from Elise M. Barry concerning additional information on Edvard Bech., May 10, 1991; Item 218 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Rosenlund and the National Register of Historic Sites, 1990 - 1991; 4.4; Box: 2 Folders 2
    - Addendum to information on Rosenlund., November 1990; Item 219 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - National Register Nomination for the Rosenlund Estate Stone Buildings at Marist College., January 1991; Item 220 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - United States Department of the Interior: National Park Service: National Register of Historic Places Registration form for the Rosenlund Estate Buildings., January 3, 1991; Item 221 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - United States Department of the Interior: National Park Service: National Register of Historic Places Registration form for the Rosenlund Estate Buildings Bibliographical References., Item 222 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Letter to Viggo B. Rambusch from Dennis J. Murray thanking him for a copy of the article on Edvard Bech and informing him that the Rosenlund buildings were added to the State Register of Historical Buildings., May 20, 1991; Item 223 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Copy of Dennis J. Murray’s “A Lasting Ideal in a Changing World: A History of Marist College.”, undated; Item 224 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Information on Henri Braem, 1881 - 2003; 4.5; Box: 2 Folder: 3
    - Information, in Dutch, about the Braem family., undated; Item 225 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Information on Henri Braem and his family., undated; Item 226 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Copy of letter to Jorgen Bech from Henri Braem., June 29, 1888; Item 227 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Copy of letter to Jorgen Bech from Henri Braem., February 9, 1892; Item 228 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - List of telephone owners in Massachusetts in 1881., Undated (1881); Item 229 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Copy of letter to Jorgen Bech from Henri Braem., February 3, 1893; Item 230 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Copy of letter to Jorgen Bech from Henri Braem., January 22, 1894; Item 231 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Copy of letter to Jorgen Bech from Henri Braem, January 29, 1895; Item 232 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Article from the Pittsfield Sun announcing the marriage of Henri Braem’s daughter Josephine., October 10, 1895; Item 233 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Copy of letter to Jorgen Bech from Henri Braem., January 16, 1896; Item 234 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Article from the Pittsfield Sun concerning a mysterious wreck of furniture at Henri Braem’s home., October 4, 1888; Item 235 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Copy of page from John Gable’s “The Goodness that Doth Crown Our Days” (History of Trinity Parish, Lenox)., undated; Item 236 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Excerpt from Reports, Constitution, By-Laws and List of Members of the Century Association for the Year 1900, concerning the death of Henri Braem., undated; Item 237 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Letter to Catha and Viggo Rambusch from Cornelia “Nini” Brooke Gilder asking for help researching Henri Braem., May 3, 2001; Item 238 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Letter to Mrs. Cornelia B. Gilder concerning the obituary of Henri Braem., February 9, 2002; Item 239 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Letter (in German) to Viggo B. Rambusch from Dr. Waltraud Stangl concerning the obituary of Henri Braem., March 11, 2003; Item 240 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Picture of Henry M. Braem’s house in New York City, from the book New York 1880., undated; Item 241 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Picture of Henry M Braem’s house in New York City, from George B. Post, Architect by Sarah Bradford Landau., undated; Item 242 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Picture of Henri M. Braem’s house “Ethelwyn”., undated; Item 243 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Copy of article from the Poughkeepsie Courier about the Will of Elizabeth Bech- June 6? 1900., Item 244 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- 5. The Edvard Bech Monograph, 5; Box: 2 Folders: 4 - 5
  Series contains correspondance regarding the Edvard Bech Monograph and drafts of the monograph.
  - Correspondence concerning the Edvard Bech Monograph, 1952 - 2008; 5.1; Boxes: 2 Folder: 4
    - Letter in Danish., Febuary 7, 1952; Item 245 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Letter in Danish from K. Salicath., Febuary 5, 1985; Item 246 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Copy of a letter to Advokat K. Salicath from Viggo B. Rambusch offering to write a monograph about the life of Edvard Bech., June 21, 1989; Item 247 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Letter to Viggo B. Rambusch from K. Salicath confirming the interest in a monograph about Edvard Bech., July 11, 1989; Item 248 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Letter to Viggo B. Rambusch from Eric Tillisch concerning information about Sophy Margareth Oxholm., May 1, 1990; Item 249 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Letter to Viggo B. Rambusch from K. Salicath sending funds., May 2, 1990; Item 250 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Letter to Viggo B. Rambusch from Sophie Bardram apologizing for not having any information on Sophy Oxholm., August 30, 1990; Item 251 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Letter to Viggo B. Rambusch from K. Salicath concerning his poor health and giving contact information for Suzanne Thorball., September 3, 1990; Item 252 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Copy of a letter to Jesse Effron from Viggo B. Rambusch stating that he would be interested in writing an article about Edvard Bech., September 12, 1990; Item 253 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Letter to Suzanne Thorball from Viggo B. Rambusch asking her to get information about Edvard Bech from Mr. Salicath., September 25, 1990; Item 254 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Letter to Viggo B. Rambusch from Jesse Effron concerning his letter to the Dutchess County Historical Society., October 15, 1990; Item 255 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Letter to Viggo B. Rambusch from Edward Bech., November 28, 1990; Item 256 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Copy of a transmittal sheet from Viggo B. Rambusch to Jesse Effron., April 19, 1991; Item 257 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Letter to Viggo B. Rambusch from Jesse Effron thanking him for the article., April 29, 1991; Item 258 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Copy of a letter to Advokat Knud Salicath from Viggo B. Rambusch informing him of the Dutchess County Historical Society’s interest in Edvard Bech., May 1, 1991; Item 259 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Letter to Viggo B. Rambusch from Walter Averill concerning information from the Adriance Library., June 10, 1991; Item 260 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Copy of a letter to Edward Jorgen Bech from Viggo B. Rambusch sending a version of the publication about Edvard Bech in the Dutchess County Historical Society’s Yearbook., June 27, 1991; Item 261 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Copy of a letter to Advocat Knud Salicath from Viggo B. Rambusch asking him to translate two attached articles from Danish., November 11, 1991; Item 262 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Copy of a letter to Advocat Knud Salicath from Viggo B. Rambusch applying for a subsidy to continue his work and informing him of the inclusion of the Rosenlund buildings on the National Register of Historic Buildings., January 13, 1992; Item 263 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Copy of a letter to Advocat Knud Salicath from Viggo B. Rambusch informing him of a new version of his Edvard Bech article and asking for a translation of two death notices., April 23, 1992; Item 264 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Copy of a letter to Advocat Knud Salicath from Viggo B. Rambusch sending seven copies of his article about Edvard Bech and asking for extra funds if possible., January 22, 1993; Item 265 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Copy of a letter to Eric Tillisch from Viggo B. Rambusch sending him a copy of an article he wrote., February 5, 1993; Item 266 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Copy of a letter to Edward J. A. Bech from Viggo B. Rambusch sending copies of the article Rambusch wrote about Edvard Bech., February 5, 1993; Item 267 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Copy of a letter to August and Elisabeth Bech from Viggo B. Rambusch sending them a copy of the article about Edvard Bech., February 5, 1993; Item 268 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Letter to Susanne Estrup from Viggo B. Rambusch asking if they could meet while in Denmark., August 26, 2002; Item 269 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Letter to Susanne Estrup from Viggo B. Rambusch., Febuary 22, 2008; Item 270 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence between Viggo B. Rambusch and Stephen Sinon concerning background information on Dr. David Hosack., March 2008; Item 271 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Drafts of the Edvard Bech monograph, 5.2; Box: 2 Folder: 5
    - First draft with a typed preface, handwritten notes, and copies of letters/pictures that were to be included in the monograph., undated; Item 271 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Second draft., January 7, 1992; Item 272 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Third draft., June 3, 1992; Item 273 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Final draft., undated; Item 274 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Photocopies of pictures used., undated; Item 275 (Box 2, Folder 5)